Dorcas Olaniyan Frontend Developer

olaniyandorcas91@gmail.com

**** 07069637222

in

https://www.linkedin.com/in/dorcas-olaniyan-114228143

https://github.com/Mhizdhee

Profile

Driven and enthusiastic web developer with a strong passion for creating user-friendly, beautiful and exceptional web experiences. I'm proficient in Html, Css, TailwindCss, Javascript, React.js, Materia UI, Chakra UI,Git and GitHub. I'm committed to staying up to date with latest trends and technologies to ensure the best user experience. I possess good communication skill, hardworking, ability to work individually and as part of a team, with commitment to continuous learning and professional growth.

Education

2018 – 2019 Lagos, Nigeria	Master of Business Administration (MBA) University of Lagos
2010 - 2015	Food Science and Technology (BSC)
Ogun, Nigeria	Federal University of Agriculture Abeokuta

Professional Experience

2023/07 - present Lagos, Nigeria

Frontend Developer

YellowDot Africa

• YD Video Portal Project

- 1. Collaborated with the design team to implement visually appealing and intuitive user interfaces.
- 2. Worked closely with other frontend developers to ensure seamless integration of frontend components.
- 3. Engaged in regular communication with backend developers to synchronize frontend and backend functionalities.
- 4. Implemented responsive design principles for seamless viewing on various devices.
- 5. Overcame challenges in optimizing video loading times, resulting in a 20% increase in user retention.

• YD Trivia Game Project

- 1. Developed frontend components for an interactive trivia game, contributing to a dynamic user interface.
- 2. Utilized React.js to create real-time updates and interactive quiz features.
- 3. Collaborated with the design team to ensure a visually appealing and intuitive gaming experience.
- 4. Collaborated with backend developers to integrate APIs, ensuring seamless communication between frontend and backend systems.
- 5. Engaged in ongoing communication with the backend team to troubleshoot and resolve integration issues.

• YD Admin Dashboard (Ongoing)

- Currently involved in the frontend development of an admin dashboard, contributing to project architecture.
- Implemented data visualization components and user dashboards for enhanced analytics.
- Collaborating closely with backend developers to ensure seamless integration of features.

Frontend Developer

P2vest Technology Limited

• ICS Report Integration on Rotura Dashboard

- 1. Collaborated with backend developers to integrate APIs, ensuring communication between frontend and backend systems.
- 2. Worked closely with other front-end developers to ensure seamless integration of front-end components.
- 3. Developed and integrated an ICS report portal onto the existing dashboard.

• Revve Dashboard

- 1. Collaborated with a team of developers to design and implement a user-friendly dashboard for Revve.
- 2. Designed transaction management table for the backoffice using React js and Antd Design.
- 3. Integrated frontend and backend APIs for seamless transaction processing, Implemented filtering, sorting, and pagination for efficient transaction management.
- 4. Developed frontend and backend APIs for tier management, Ensured scalable and secure tier architecture.
- 5. Collaborated with team members to ensure seamless integration and bug-free deployment

2022/10 - 2023/06 Lagos, Nigeria

Frontend Developer

Stutern (Stutern Graduate Accelerator)

- 1. Collaborated with the design team to implement user interfaces (UI) and user experiences (UX) using React.js, Tailwind CSS, and Material UI and translated design mock-ups or wireframes into functional web pages.
- 2. Implemented a modular components architecture using React, allowing for code reusability and faster development iterations across multiple projects.
- 3. Writing and maintaining clean, efficient, and well-documented code, debugged and troubleshooting issues that may arise during development or testing.
- 4. Collaborating with other team members, including designers, and backend developers, to understand project requirements and deliver high-quality front-end solutions.
- 5. Used version control systems like Git to manage code repositories and collaborate with other developers.

Skills

HTML	• • • •	CSS	• • • •
JavaScript	• • • • •	React	• • • • •
Tailwind Css	• • • • •	Material UI	• • • • •
Chakra UI	• • • • •	GIT	• • • • •
GITHUB	• • • • •	Antd Design	• • • • •